Believe in hope.
Southpaw is a action, drama film directed by Antoine Fuqua.
Billy "The Great" Hope, the reigning junior middleweight boxing champion, has an
impressive career, a loving wife and daughter, and a lavish lifestyle.
However, when tragedy strikes, Billy hits rock bottom,
losing his family, his house and his manager.
He soon finds an unlikely savior in Tick Willis, a former fighter
who trains the city's toughest amateur boxers.
With his future on the line, Hope fights to reclaim
the trust of those he loves the most.
Billy 'The Great'  Hope, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Maureen Hope, played by Rachel McAdams.
Titus 'Tick' Wills, played by Forest Whitaker.
Leila Hope, played by Oona Laurence.
Jordan Mains, played by 50 Cent.
Hoppy, played by Skylan Brooks.
Southpaw is a 2015 American sports drama film directed by Antoine Fuqua, written by Kurt
Sutter and starring Jake Gyllenhaal, Forest Whitaker and Rachel McAdams.
The film follows a boxer who sets out to get his life back on track after losing his wife
to gun violence and later his young daughter to child protective services.
The film was released on July 24, 2015, by The Weinstein Company.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, while Gyllenhaal and
Oona Laurence's performances received positive reviews.
The film grossed $94.2 million worldwide against a
production budget of $30 million.
The film is set in New York City, but it was filmed in
Pittsburgh and the nearby town of Indiana, Pennsylvania.
The film marked one of the last films to be scored by James Horner and the first of three posthumous
releases to feature his music (the other two being The 33 and The Magnificent Seven).
The film and the film's soundtrack album are dedicated to his memory.
The film explores themes of sports, fighter, tragedy, death, boxing.
The tone is emotional.